Guide to the Constance Stuart Larrabee collection, 1935-2000 COR0011.MS
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Photos, contact sheets, and negatives, 1935-2000; Series 1
  - WWII prints, 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 3
    - Press prints: Men walking up snowy hillside, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Press prints: Snowy country scenery, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Press prints: Congratulations on a job well done, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Press prints: Big gun, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Press prints: Man smoking, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Press prints: Fallen statue, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Press prints: woman selling papers, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 27)
    - War correspondents: San Marino, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 28)
    - War correspondents: Two men shaking hands, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Press prints: Miscellaneous, circa 1944; Series 1 subseries 3 (Box 3, Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Portraits, 1935-2000; Series 1 subseries 4
    Contains photographs of Constance Stuart Larrabee taken throughout her life by unidentified photographers. Materials date from 1935-2000.
    - Possibly Munich, Germany - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 5 friends in front of Rolandseck's cafe/restaurant in the snow, 1935-1936; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Munich, Germany - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 3 friends in snow, 1935-1936; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Pretoria - Constance Stuart Larrabee formal portrait used for war correspondent ID card, 1944 May; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cairo - General Frank Theron and Constance Stuart Larrabee, giving each other a look, 1944 August; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 4)
    - French Rivera - Constance Stuart Larrabee washing clothes in a helmet, 1944 August 21; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Rome - Constance Stuart Larrabee with women, possibly Eli or Jackie Martin, 1944; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 6)
    - St Maxime - Constance Stuart Larrabee with Leon Gaumont, age 82, at his villa, 1944 August 26; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 7)
    - St Maxime - Constance Stuart Larrabee with Americans at the 58th Medical Headquarters, 1944 August 26; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Sisteron - Constance Stuart Larrabee with major WG Andrew and Captain Jimmy Hunt of the British Army with two children, 1944 August 26; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 9)
    - St Maxime - Constance Stuart Larrabee and 3 German prisoners by a Red Cross truck, 1944 August; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Possibly Besancon, France - Constance Stuart Larrabee standing in rubble, wearing pants, 1944 September; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Possibly Besancon, France - Constance Stuart Larrabee by Under Enemy Observation sign, 1944 September; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Paris, France - Constance Stuart Larrabee in front of the Arc de Triomphe, 1944 October; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Strasburg, Germany - Constance Stuart Larrabee in front of several signs, 1944 November 25; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - France - Constance Stuart Larrabee by French P.R.O. sign, 1944; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cairo - Constance Stuart Larrabee with camel, women, and can, 1945 February; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Possibly South Africa - Close up with Constance Stuart Larrabee sitting in Jeep, 1945 March; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Possibly South Africa - Constance Stuart Larrabee with Rolleri and Jeep, 1945 March; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Possibly South Africa - Constance Stuart Larrabee standing in Jeep, 1945 March; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Possibly South Africa - Constance Stuart Larrabee in Jeep, 1945 March; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Possibly South Africa - Constance Stuart Larrabee sitting on hood of Jeep, 1945 March; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Possibly Cairo - Constance Stuart Larrabee walking away from Jeeps and plane, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Possibly Cairo - Constance Stuart Larrabee posing in front of plane propeller, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Possibly Egypt - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 2 women and 4 navy men, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Possibly Egypt - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 6 people in front of plane, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Pretoria - Constance Stuart Larrabee standing on steps to plane, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Possibly Italy - Constance Stuart Larrabee with man in uniform in front of juice stand, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - London - Constance Stuart Larrabee with man in uniform and policeman at corner of Whitehall and Downing, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Possibly Paris - Constance Stuart Larrabee standing with man in uniform, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Possibly Paris - Constance Stuart Larrabee sitting on tank with two soldiers, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Location unknown - Constance Stuart Larrabee with large group in front of plane, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Location unknown - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 3 soldiers eating bread, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Location unknown - Constance Stuart Larrabee with friends on stairs, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Location unknown - Constance Stuart Larrabee posing with wing bomber soldier and puppy by plane, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Location unknown - Constance Stuart Larrabee with 3 people in uniform around a decorative urn, circa 1944-1945; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Chestertown, MD - Color print, fuzzy, of Constance Stuart Larrabee with dove, circa 1980-2000; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chestertown, MD - Constance Stuart Larrabee wearing a striped jacket with dog, circa 1980-2000; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Chestertown, MD - Constance Stuart Larrabee seated, on porch with two dogs, circa 1980-2000; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Chestertown, MD - Constance Stuart Larrabee standing with two dogs on porch, circa 1980-2000; Series 1 subseries 4 (Box 3, Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition installations and openings, 1984-1990; Series 1 subseries 5
    Contains photographs taken at exhibitions and exhibition openings of Constance Stuart Larrabee's work. Bulk of material taken at the exhibition "WWII Photo Journal" at The National Women of Women in the Arts in 1989. Materials date from 1984-1990.
    - WWII Photo Journal - National Museum of Women in the Arts opening, 1989; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 1)
    - WWII Photo Journal - Greensboro Historical Museum installation, circa 1989-1990; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 2)
    - WWII Photo Journal - Southwestern Michigan College installation, circa 1990; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 3)
    - WWII Photo Journal - Bayly Art Museum installation, circa 1990; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 4)
    - Other Shows - Tribal Photographs opening, circa 1984; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 5)
    - Other Shows - Life in Wartime, Constance Stuart Larrabee and Gordon Parks, undated; Series 1 subseries 5 (Box 5, Box 1, Segment 6)
- Publications and textual materials, 1941-2000; Series 2
  Arranged in 3 subseries: Publications; Textual materials; and Books.
  Contains textual records of Constance Stuart Larrabee, including books, clippings, correspondence, and writing published in Liberatas magazine and Spotlight magazine. Materials date from 1941-2000.
  - Publications, 1944-1987; Series 2 subseries 1
    Contains records of Constance Stuart Larrabee's writing and photography published in Liberatas magazine and Spotlight magazine, and shared through radio broadcast. Materials date from 1944-1987.
    - Radio broadcasts, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Liberatas - Captions Spool A, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Liberatas - Captions Spool A1, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Liberatas - Captions Spool B, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Liberatas - Captions Miscellaneous 1, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Liberatas - Captions Miscellaneous 2, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Liberatas - Diary - letter format, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Liberatas - Diary - S. France Invasion, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Liberatas - Diary - typed, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Liberatas - Text, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Liberatas - Original publication, 1945 February; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Liberatas - Original publication, 1945 March; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Liberatas - Original - Not WWII content, 1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jeep Trek - String-bound manuscript, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Jeep Trek - Manuscript 2nd edit, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Jeep Trek - Xerox, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Jeep Trek - Xerox [notes for Photo Journal], 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Jeep Trek - Revisions, 1985; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Jeep Trek - Revisions, 1987; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Jeep Trek - Transition to WWII Photo Journal, 1944-1946; Series 2 subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Textual materials, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2
    Contains correspondence, clippings, and files from Constance Stuart Larrabee's professional work and for her funeral service. Materials date from 1985-2000.
    - Corcoran, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Creative Camera, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Edit, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Other Shows, 1985-2000; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folders 25-34)
    - Funeral Pamphlets, 2000 September 9; Series 2 subseries 2 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Books, 1941-1994; Series 2 subseries 3
    Contains books collected by Constance Stuart Larrabee and relating to war and military history. Publication dates range from 1941-1994.
    - Baggage to the Enemy by Edward Ardizzone, 1941; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 1)
    - Flying Crusader: The Story of General William Mitchell Pioneer of Air Power by Isaac Don Levine, 1943; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 2)
    - The New Yorker Book of War Pieces London, 1939 to Hiroshima, 1945, 1947; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 3)
    - This is the Story by David L. Cohn, 1947; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 4)
    - Winged Dagger: Adventures on Special Service by Roy Farran, 1948; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 5)
    - The World of Bemelmans by Ludwig Bemelmans, 1955; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 6)
    - The Patton Papers, 1885-1940, 1972; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 7)
    - West with the Night by Beryl Markham, 1983; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 8)
    - What War Taught Me About Peace by Robert Muller, 1985; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 9)
    - Ernie's War: The Best of Ernie Pyle's World War II Dispatches edited with a biographical essay by David Nichols, 1986; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 10)
    - Women of the World: The Great Foreign Correspondents by Julia Edwards, 1988; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 11)
    - D-Day: The Invasion in Photographs edited by Tony Hall, 1994; Series 2 subseries 3 (Box 5, Item 12)
- WWII Documents and artifacts, 1936-1946; Series 3
  Contains documents and artifacts collected and created by Constance Stuart Larrabee while working as a war correspondent for South Africa during World War II. Materials date from 1936-1945.
  - Correspondence, 1936-1965; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - News Articles: Girl at the Front, 1945 February 20; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - News Articles, 1945-1960; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - News Articles: Record of Company C, 1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Route forms and Permits, 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Memorabilia, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - WWII scrapbook, 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Notepad, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Identification card, 1944 May 16; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - ID card and paybook, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Address books, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Prints of Special pass and ID card, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Booklets, 1945; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Nazi party badge, circa 1940-1944; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 1)
  - French Forces of the Interior (FFI) armband, circa 1944-1945; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 2)
  - US Army 1st Armored Division patch, circa 1940-1946; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 3)
  - Seventh United States Army patch, circa 1943-1945; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 4)
  - US Army II Corps patch, circa 1940-1945; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 5)
  - Army Services Forces patch, 1942-1946; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 6)
  - War correspondent shoulder board, circa 1940-1946; Series 3 (Box 5, Box 2, Item 7)
- Exhibitions, 1945-1993; Series 4
  Arranged in 2 subseries: Exhibition for The South African Red Cross Society; and WWII Photo Journal.
  Contains exhibition catalogue drafts, planning documents, prints, and travel documentation for exhibitions of Constance Stuart Larrabee's photography. Materials date from 1945-1993.
  - Exhibition for The South African Red Cross Society, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1
    Contains documents and prints from Constance Stuart Larrabee's 1945 exhibition of photographs for The South African Red Cross Society at Schwickerdt's Gallery.
    - Invitation, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Reviews, xerox copies, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Reviews, original clippings, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Negatives, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee with 2 men, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee with woman under USA 7th Army sign, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Prints: Installation shot - USA 7th Army, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Prints: Installation shot - 9 portraits of men, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Prints: Installation shot - 17 portraits, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Prints: Installation shot - Paris images, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Prints: Installation shot - Strasburg and Rome images, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee seated with man speaking in front of map, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee speaking with two men, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee with group of exhibition attendees, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Prints: Constance Stuart Larrabee with 2 people, 1945; Series 4 subseries 1 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 15)
  - WWII Photo Journal, 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2
    Contains planning and production documents for the 1989 exhibition of Constance Stuart Larrabee photography WWII Photo Journal at The National Museum of Women in the Arts.
    - Catalogue - drafts, circa 1988-1989; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Catalogue - preliminary text, circa 1988-1989; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Catalogue - production, circa 1988-1989; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue - final product, 1989; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Production, circa 1989; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sites - national publicity report, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sites - press office packet, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Sites - registrar packet, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Sites - education/ program department packet, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - National Museum of Women in the Arts - publicity, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - National Musuem of Women in the Arts - fan mail, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Washington College, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Putnam Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Cantor Art Gallery, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Travelling Exhibition - University of Missouri, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Travelling Exhibition - U of M Danah Coester, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Greensboro Historical Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Travelling Exhibition - War Museum of Virginia, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Los Alamos Historical Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Travelling Exhibition - American Museum of Science and Energy, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Roger Guffey Gallery, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Travelling Exhibitoin - Rogers Historical Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Southwestern Michigan College, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Museum of Cape Fear, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Travelling Exhibition - The Monmouth Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Washington State Historical Society, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Travelling Exhibition - Bayly Art Museum, circa 1989-1993; Series 4 subseries 2 (Box 6, Folder 27)